all right welcome back
um
we're in the second discussion on
chapter 3 so does anyone just have any
quote or question or anything to kind of
begin
with
any thoughts or we can just start to
look at the the written questions from
before or some page or figure from
three
a a basic sort of disorienting thing uh
I guess in the uh diagram at the top of
page
44 um where it shows external States
internal States action States and
sensory States I'm confused uh about
what are realistic examples of like
influence on that direct Arrow between
active States and sensory States like
again I understand active State or the
point of active State generally is to
impact upon the world and like
eventually we see the effects of that in
sensory States but I guess the direct
Double Arrow between the active States
and sensory States seems confusing to
me yeah it doesn't have to have any
influence in the real
system but it's it it it could but I
think in a if we if the sensors and
actuators of the system are
separate then that edge may have no
effect but in principle it
exists because the the the states are
not like pre-tagged
it's always just based upon the choice
the internal
state so a causal edge here
in sketching out the specific system
You' quickly determine like whether it's
something causal in the system or not
but we'll see if it comes up in any of
the
examples
Susan uh yes um so can you I'm really
unclear in what the what are the
boundaries
between
um the um inference the the external and
internal States in other words
specifically what is action in this
context and I I'm wrestling with speech
acts um you know not doing something is
still an action on your environment if
you think about it
so yes well one aspect of action that is
um not really looked at in the textbook
is deciding when to act like in the kind
of simplest format of the action
perception Loop there's just a
perception and an action every single
time step so the like the choice to like
wait versus to do something at
all um sometimes that's brought in as
like a null action
okay yeah just like an action that kind
of like keeps you where you
are okay there could be a nested model
where the top is a binary decision you
know make a move or not within make a
move there's just the four moves um okay
is is that have anything to do with the
um transition
function the um the the
transition function
is describing how the state the hidden
States change through time so it's the B
Matrix we're getting an
observations okay and then the a kind of
maps the observations to yeah the hidden
States so from the thermometer readings
to the temperature in the room and then
the transition function is the
temperature of the room changing per
delta T just per time
interval the temperature in the
room underlying
changing and the formulas on the right
there you know that's actually for the
transition
functions yeah so then what okay three
here yep which is B it's saying it's the
distribution of the state at the next
time point okay conditioned upon the
state at the current time point and the
policy so say okay the temperature of
the room at the next time point is
conditioned upon the current temperature
in the room and whether I'm turning on
the air conditioner or not okay okay and
then which policy is like selecting
which slice of b gets applied as the
transition function and one last
question um so is this is this model
just saying that there was a move made
and there was a and that's a SE is that
is
that you know as I'm seeing two
different is that perception action or
is that just a different action
repeating in the picture you know just
looking at the yeah like the fact that
there's two threes
here no actually because you got the
upper and the lower so is that the
higher high road low road no um so 4.3
the
top graph is the discrete time model and
the lower graph is the continuous time
model okay and then in
um here's just the discrete time model
okay just the top half of figure
4.3 okay so here again we see the B and
it's hidden State at the next time point
to plus one y conditioned upon the
current state and the
policy
okay thank
you and and I think as we kind of may
have alluded to earlier there's
like this representation of the
generative model which is the partially
observable marov decision process and
then there's this particular
partition
representation so here we have the kind
of
hinting at a
circularity and the
flows because the dot on top is the
derivative so the flows across these
four
states which we can associate with the
um from the perspective of these
internal States as the sensory action
and
external and then there's this
form which is more like a branching tree
a little
bit because here like the observations
are a dead
end okay I don't exactly remember what
we got to last week but I think we
looked at figure 3.2
with the Scatter
Plots um does anyone want to ask a
question or should we just try to go
through
these
Thomas oh I'm sorry that was a hiccup by
accident I
apologize okay all right let's look
through some of
these um what's the difference between
the terms basium brain hypothesis
predictive processing predictive coding
active inference so here's it's um
discussed in several
places here's one reference
um these terms can be just kind of
broadly used to refer to very
similar uh theories and kinds of models
or if you really get down to Last Mile
they could differ um basian brain
hypothesis hypothesis suggesting it's
something that could be tested and
falsified for a given system like you
could hypothesize that the brain is
doing basian computation or is doing
something that can be modeled with
basian computation you could hypothesize
that and have criteria for why you would
accept that hypothesis or not and then
you might as well um do that and then
find out or not so this is testable
hypothesis describing whether brains
which are just some systems in the world
but a tiny subset of systems do basian
computation however they do it or
whatever their distributions are um
active
inference probably a lot of ways to
Define it in a broader sense it could
just refer to models that have action
included within the scope of inference
like models that do sense making and
action selection or to be more specific
we might be talking about active
inference models like perception action
models under the free energy principle
which is kind of chapter three high road
and then predictive processing and
predictive coding again these are
sometimes used like
interchangeably but um to get technical
about it predictive processing is the
kinds of architectures that'll get
visited in this textbook
where there's a multiscale model and um
higher levels are making predictions
about lower levels and um the entire
processing architecture has to do with
predictions hence predictive processing
predictive
coding kind of nuances that a little bit
and highlights that the messages that
are being passed incode predictions and
prediction
errors
so you have prediction process
predictive processing systems that that
do predictive
coding you could also design one that
had like one or the
other so they're all really
related but they're not exactly exactly
the same
CH if one defines preferred States as
expected
States then one can say that living
organisms must minimize the surprise of
their sensory observation I'm not clear
on the ontology here is it that
preference is the same as expectation or
that formally we can use them in the
same
equation these are lot of partial
related questions
here
[Music]
um
I'm not I don't remember if we looked at
this one last
week when we're talking about the
variable called preference
C it's a distribution over
observations I think last week we talked
about how expectation can be used in
kind of two senses one is the
expectation is like about an event that
hasn't happened yet and that's a
conversational usage of what we expect
to happen in the future also a given
distribution can have the expectation
calculated of it that's the fancy e and
that's the same thing is saying the the
central tendency or the mean of that
distribution
um in the case of pragmatic value in
expected free energy equation
2.6 yes when we talk about we're talking
about an expectation about
observations but just saying expectation
alone is almost not a complete sentence
because you need to so it's like saying
well I'm talking about the mean but the
mean of what
variable so there's settings where um
it's clear from Context what it means
and that we're talking about the same
variable but you could also Imagine a
situation where you're talking about the
central Tendencies or the future
possibilities of other variables so it's
not the terms are simply identical by
definition it's that in certain kinds of
generative models they're described the
same way to highlight that there isn't
the proposal of like a reward function
but rather there's a direct surprise
bounding on expectation um
Aaron yeah well okay this isn't exactly
a refinement of this question but it's
related I I guess like I I have been
struggling with how to think about uh I
I guess the distinction between priors
and preferences in contexts where you in
advance of receiving some observation
have reason to
expect uh and I think the narrow sense
um that conditions will be other than
you would prefer right so if the weather
report this morning says is going to be
115 in the afternoon and I you know my
car rigs down and I got before I I open
the car door to get out on the side of
the road I expect it to be uncomfortable
and challenging to my body's need for
homostasis I guess like
in maybe it's not an ontological
distinction but I am struggling with
like the uh uh under what conditions is
reasonable to sub uh to substitute
um a distribution that describes
preferred States into to a context where
where you would be talking about a
distribution that describes your belief
about States prior to getting more
information about them yeah great
question so let's just say we're talking
about temperature so our um C preference
distribution is going to be like
homeostasis just a a a gaussian
distribution around
37c so we're going to talk about that as
our preferences now it's also a prior
that's why these things are like not
complete sentences it's not that there's
one variable just only and always called
prior because any distribution that
could be updated you might be talking
about the prior distribution of that
distribution so hence it's it's like
when talking about like beliefs it's
like about which one of these priors
prior distribution about which one now
when people don't further Define which
prior they're talking about usually
they're talking about D the prior on
hidden States
so let's just say that um we're we're in
the desert and we we have an accurate
thermometer so our a matrix is is just
the identity Matrix just the ones on the
diagonal so we're just getting accurate
thermometer
readings um we prefer 37 in terms of our
homeostasis but our prior belief is that
it's going to be
50 and then we get a thermometer reading
of 50 and then that's consistent with
the hidden State estimate of the
temperature being
50 so there's totally no issue
with preferences over observations
interfering with the sense making
process because C doesn't come into play
with a or
D however the the C
does shape action through a pragmatic
value
but C doesn't play a role in sense
making or in um estimating future time
steps at
all
is there a minimal example of a
thing is it correct to say a thing is
the temporary Persistence of a marov
blanket perhaps that it's the
Persistence of something that can be
modeled as or with a Maron blanket
are all things then just not an
equilibrium steady state processes well
considered one way they're at an
equilibria point to allow them to be
measured but by virtue of our scenario
overall being dissipative the fact that
they're
existing is non-e
equilibrium do we need to be more strict
in saying these things are are only
self- evidencing things rather than
things in the colloquial
sense totally depends on what what's
being
discussed if it's an inner
particle then it may not be providing
any extra information to say that it's
self- evidencing like to say that rock
is fulfilling predictions that it
expects to be there
um first issue you may not be adding any
richness to the account and second off
you're proposing a map that's that's
indicating some causal
um capacities for the rock that are
unrealistic whereas when you start
getting into that squirrel is acting
like
XYZ then you are creating parsimonious
accounts of behavior that can't be
accounted with simpler and you are
making maps that have features that that
system might actually
have so the squirrel self-
evidencing
um it's probably more of a value ad in
terms of the account and it's probably
more plausible
mechanistically what is the counterpart
in an active agent to conserve versus
disputed physical
systems what is the analogy to friction
in a cognitive system how strong is this
analogy that's an interesting question
to explore one possibility is like what
is heat and what is
work in basian
mechanics like if if all of the
information of the observation were
used for belief updating that would be
like extracting 100% of the efficiency
of the fuel if you if you perfectly
burnt the
fuel the maximum extractable heat as
work would be like
from the hydrocarbon down to whatever
the um terminal product of burning was
like you could burn the candle and
extract all the heat from the candle um
or like how they test how much calor are
in food like you just burn it and
there's a Max am of energy to extract so
then by analogy there's like a maximum
amount of information to extract from a
given signal like described by its
entropy so there might be something like
how much of the entropy of the signal is
going
into belief updating versus how much is
being um partitioned to like dis
itive but I'm not sure about friction
specifically because friction isn't just
the same as
heat okay chapter 3 High
Road starts from premise that to survive
any living organism has to maintain
itself in a suitable set of preferred
States these preferred states are first
and foremost defined by Niche specific
evolutionary
adaptations however as we will see later
in advanced organisms these can also
extend to learned cognitive
goals I'm curious about the
applicability of active inference to
social structures such as economic
systems firms self-organizing groups and
government systems amongst others one
can argue that social systems have
preferred States created from both
evolutionary Niche and learn cognitive
mechanisms has active inference yet been
applied to these sorts of
systems
yeah cool that some people have added
some
links yes applied to a limited
extent Al explains in the intro video
Markov blanket is a boundary in the
state space not necessarily a spatial
temporal boundary
if we were talking about a spatial
temporal State space like GPS
coordinates comma time then a boundary
in the GPS comma time
space would be a state space boundary
corresponding to a spatial temporal
boundary but if our state space were
talking about something that wasn't
spatial temporal then the mark called
blanket is not necessarily spatial
temporal even in the map even before get
getting into the map territory stuff
what allows the agent to be
statistically separated from its
boundary as observed there's
blanket so I take it the blanket is a
lens through which the agent observes
their
environment
yes
yes would this lens be defined by their
affordances yes just like on the inbound
it's kind of like glasses like they're a
real like a lens and then like light
comes in and gets focused in but then
also if it were a light source it would
defract out the other way it's not
exactly the same because inbound
perception isn't exactly the same as
outbound action but it is like a two-way
lens that has communication across
interface
Susan wait unmute but then yes
Susan oh sorry um
so I was listening to one of the uh
videos and I've heard um priston say
that Markoff blankets were you were
really just about computational
models what do you have to say about
that like he meant that they were being
introduced as a computational tool
rather than like an ontological Claim
about reality or what did you okay okay
that makes sense thank
you like let's just say we had um 10
variables we could test a model that
every variable influenced each other so
um and and and every three-way
combination matters uniquely and every
five way and seven and nine way it's
like we could test kind of the the
fullest possible model but that's more
parameters to
estimate so it reduces the St
statistical power per parameter so this
is a fundamental trade-off in
statistical
modeling which is like um the fewer
variables you include for a given sample
size the more statistical power you
have however you run the risk of
partitioning variants
inappropriately whereas the more
variables you
include that may come closer into
alignment with what is like believed to
be kind of like a a very
multicausal
Nexus so it can kind of feel nice and
appropriate to enable the possibility of
of intersections mattering for
causality however that can make the
causal State spaces very
large diluting the statistical power to
detect
anything and so models are chosen to be
at a trade-off point
between strongly explaining two few
factors and weakly explaining too many
factors and that's why how many
parameters are included in that kind of
best performing trade-off model that
kind of parameter estimation is about
the map not about the territory
does the distinction between active
learning and active inference have to do
these Imports I don't remember exactly
which paper the active learning
was
but it kind I remembered that
like again like sometimes the term is
used in a narrow or a broad sense like
in a broad sense Active Learning and
active inference are the same thing they
could both be used to describe a system
that's active and learning but then if
you really get into it a paper might say
well we're using this to to mean this
specifically so without the link I I I
don't remember exactly what what was
meant by Active Learning
are internal State parameters referring
to the edge of the marov state
space no they're referring
to the
inside the marov blanket is The Edge
like the crust around the internal State
parameters
is there any identification for the
edge of a Markoff
blanket like
whichever whatever variable you're going
to point to and say that's the one that
I'm going to call
internal so that's just that's a choice
by the model which one is going to be
called
internal then all of the crust around it
all of the envelope that encloses it is
the blanket of that state but if you had
chosen a different state to choose
internal you would have ended up getting
a different set of blanketing
noes it's kind of like let's just say um
you know we're we're doing Google Maps
and so we we're going to say
um for this trip from A to B this is the
first straight this is the last smile
and then this is like the space between
but if you had chosen a different
Journey maybe the street that was in the
in between for the first journey is
going to be the first mile for this
other
journey in advanced organisms preferred
states can also extend to learn
cognitive goals
and in advanced organisms like human
they can achieve preferred states by
increasing the abstract social cultural
strategies my question is if they are
cast in terms of active inference must
all of these preferred States and
strategies be ultimately linked to
survival in some
way or in the case of advanced organisms
can free energy be related to something
other than
survival if acting that way was inom
compatible with existence you wouldn't
see it if acting that way was
deleterious to Fitness you'd see it
less so that's the kind of
um Evolution like
component which is like it doesn't mean
that every single phenomena was
necessary and
sufficient for existential success
but certainly measuring something means
that it wasn't incompatible with
existence so then by the time that we're
talking about organisms that might be um
with all kinds of different cognitive
phenomena especially if they're going to
be like in like a um a new or changing
Niche you could have um
maladaptive you have a ball rolling
downhill and you could just be observing
the last five minutes of a maladaptive
trajectory of the ball rolling downhill
so like past returns do not guarantee
future returns or whatever they
say can marov blankets be considered as
decoupling an agent in an
environment yes you could think of it as
how they are coupled which is to say how
they are
decoupled like how they are
articulated the joint is both how things
are connected and how they're
separated can surprise only be
diminished through action
so here's a quote from chapter 2 um
pointing to the two ways that
discrepancy is addressed in active
inference change the mind or change the
world so if we're in the temperature
situation we prefer it to be homeostatic
and the temperature is higher than we
expect then we can either take
affordances that we believe are going to
bring the temperature back into
alignment with our observation
preferences that's pragmatic value
change world or we could learn and come
to um dissipate the discrepancy just by
updating what we expect things to
be however for like a physiological
prior those may not be
learnable
huh um I
guess uh what happens if observation uh
were surprising and then they fall back
into um non not surprising um values
like the temperatures spiked up
unexpectedly but then it just came back
down to
normal
yes that's a good question so like
um a related question is like what
updating strategies are adaptive under
what patterns of environmental
regularity so if the environment was
like very slowly changing then a very
slow changing
um belief updating might be appropriate
if the environment were very rapidly
changing then you might want to track it
more rapidly if the environment had like
one in 10 times let's just say there was
like just a erroneous measure so if it
was like a noisy environment where
sometimes you got like wild measurements
but then they were just like part of a a
noise then you um would have something
like a CET filter which is basically
What's Happening Here in the temperature
example this kind of looks like CO2
measurements in the in the environment
too but it's kind of like you have these
noisy measurements coming in and then
the colan filter is basically saying how
can we smooth
this um in the extreme case it Smooths
just taking the moving
average in the extreme slow case in the
extreme fast case the smoothing is just
tracing exactly what you're getting but
then there's somewhere in between that
like Smooths out some of the
noise guess could you put this under the
umbrella of um the action of updating
your own
beliefs yeah like moving a belief
distribu ution could be understood as a
cognitive action like if you had the
choice to do it or not or if you had the
mental action to attend if you had the
um you have mental action on the dial of
how much to pay attention to it zero
attention to it means it's going to have
no impact on your beliefs because if you
don't pay attention to something it's as
if it didn't happen 100% attention to it
means you're going to update your
beliefs 100% to exactly whatever the the
last thing that was said was so then
that would open up an internal
policy
possibility of how much should I attend
to this
environment so then in a noisier
environment you would want to reduce
your
attention to make your
smoothing slower to average out more
whereas if you in a more precise
environment with like more um relevant
or Salient information you'd want to
increase your attention to to maximize
information
gained but then when we're measuring
supplies and you know
the you know the temperature spikes up
and then it spikes back
down I guess you could say that Spike
itself is is a surprise but then now
your your prize for the temperature is
kind of normalized again
so yeah I guess you know
like it could be a little bit confusing
on how you think about um you know
supplies is only minimized through
action but in this case it kind of feels
like it was minimized just from the
environment
itself yeah interesting
Susan so is there a a specific specific
parameter or
computation uh to account for the
capacity constraints and like cognitive
capacity or cognitive
control you know when people slip into a
state of overwhelm they're going to
change States so yeah there's that would
be a back to the transition but I didn't
know if it
was that that's really interesting I
mean let's sketch it out and explore it
because I think that's we're not going
to find that in the
minimal PDP maybe just be a state change
I guess yeah but if we if we um let's
just say that we uh we imagine two
internal states that the agent can be in
one or leg what about
[Music]
um so how about instead of um too cold
just right and just hot yeah there
there's an internal model that basically
it's the temp you know is this epistemic
is this too boring just right or is this
too
much that may not
be um like that doesn't need mean that
that's the ultimate truth like you could
have a temperature estimating agent that
actually thinks that there's a rooms
that are too hot but actually it could
do just fine to them just because it's
the agent's estimate doesn't mean that
it is that but so now there's there's um
the agent is doing um estimate it's
getting Challenge on the y-
axis and then it's estimating how
difficult is this
content and then it's doing some
estimate and then like the the accurate
estimator would have um basically would
would have would know when it was in
boring just right or too hard whereas
you could have an optimistic estimator
that you know skews to one way or the
other way and then each of those three
states might be associated with um like
maybe in the in the just right phase
maybe that's when there's a feeling like
there's the highest amount of
intentional control but then if
something's too easy or too hard
somebody might feel like they like
there's no point in exerting cognitive
control because it won't
matter well it'll matter if you have
like ADHD
and so yeah managing the that uh I mean
it's the energy it's
the um
entropy comes back to the
entropy yeah to to ordered or too
complex yep is does not
have yeah that would be good to add to
that graph the flood graph to redundant
or to novel
yeah how's markco blanket a restatement
of the classical action perception
cycle there probably a lot of ways
to
um it's a bit of a
restatement perhaps because
[Music]
um that's so funny like cybernetic agent
is
like I was
expecting like
this but hey I mean oh so for for many
decades I mean this
is more similar than not to what we've
just been discussing with predictive
processing and active inference incoming
sensors with a reference prediction and
then the differential goes on to
influence the
actuator that acts upon the external
system which then responds and then
passes another sensor
observation um so
conceptually like no one really
disagrees that observations are coming
in actions are going out and there's
like causation on both sides or you know
so the reason why the marov blanket is a
bit of a restatement is because this
cybernetic Loop was phrased before the
basian causal graph literature of the
1990s like with Judea Pearl
so octave inference
restates the classic action perception
cycle in terms of the causal graphs
that have existed since the
1990s I will say I want to say that uh
that the cybernetic um viable systems
models come a long way too so don't
throw the baby out with the bass
water no definitely not um Dave Douglas
is uh working a lot with American
cybernetic society and um and I think
that combining our Journal work with the
uh International Society for system
science and cybernetics like it will
reveal many
many yeah parallels like
this these are these are like it just
here it's like well the circle's kind of
conceptual but now we have a technical
definition for that boundary in terms of
causal graphs mark blanket or in terms
of category Theory but
[Music]
um like Robert
rosen's
ecology I don't know how useful the um
Wikipedia is but he developed a lot of
category Theory ecology models again
ones that that pre-s a lot of what
were like
here but it
just it just that it's it's a schematic
so it's very
evocative what's really different now is
there are open source software packages
and first principles
[Music]
formalism that's like this is
literally
me bar more similar than
not even this looks like those marov
blanket uh Scatter Plots in the
chapter it just so so there's just
there's more similarities than
not
hence trying to get them
all
together living system
um resolve fundamental biological
Problems by exerting active control over
their
states is the way to understand why
automatic mechanisms are active in
thinking that these are still involved
in calculating
EF but the time Horizon is small is
there another concept of passive control
or is all control
active take the example of touching the
hot
kettle
probably a lot of ways to think about
this
one
um but the automatic mechanisms being
active like I I don't think that they
always need to have
planning like for example secreting
insulin and
glucagon and hormone regulation of blood
sugar that could just be reflexive
actions like as something gets to here
then more of this hormone is secreted
and then I it goes down more of that
hormone is secreted so that's still
active control but it's just reflexive
active
control is there a concept of passive
control that's almost like action
without action or like the ability to
like control control something without
acting which you could probably design a
situation where that does happen like
where um by by
non-action the agent has the other
system um aligned with its preferences
but suffice to say it wouldn't be doing
so by virtue of actions that it took um
Erin yeah I guess riing on this and um
in the chapter and a few other places in
discussion um the the concept like
temporal depth of a system and like its
ability to plan has come up and I guess
like this is this is partly in this
question we're talking about like some
actions that a system undertakes are
informed by that temporal depth but some
actions that the same system undertakes
are really shallow like removing your
hand from the hot Kettle you don't need
to see very many steps in the future to
understand that's like the highest value
thing you can do um but so I guess that
does that that also implies something
about they being like like
a A
heterogeneity in the the thickness of
consideration of actions that the agent
is is
driving yeah definitely like the
organism is a multiscale phenomena so
even in the same moment like in might
the best map of what I was doing 1 hour
ago might have been um regulating uh
oxygen homeostasis over seconds time
scale but then you know food over a
dayong time scale but then like
Financial you know well-being over a
year so you could make multiple time
scales of
action even a slow action is happening
in a
moment and then and then the kind of no
planning model first off it's the
computationally simplest so it's a great
starting point and then you can look for
deviations um and then ask where do we
need additional phenomena to account for
what we're
seeing like like birds
flocking like the famous models don't
involve any planning it just involves
the visual field and basically it's like
if they're too close like you pull back
and then if they're like too far you
move towards them or something like
that so then if you do a model you find
that you can replicate the statistics of
this this empirical flock there's no
need to invoke planning but then maybe
there's a residual with some real system
it's like oh actually you know let's try
let's see if planning could explain that
variance Gap
Susan wait unmute then
yeah um oh
gosh was looking at one of your slides
and and
uh so I I I I totally lost in my train
of thought but I will say that I saw a
video back on the the Swarm and the
studies show that a large percentage of
the of the of the Swarm is just
following you know whoever is closest to
them so you can't overthink this
thing yeah that's that's this is a very
funny in the ass like
I I don't I think it's a little bit
sensationalist to call them lazy but it
was it's like most nestmates at most
moments are just standing there that's
excess capacity or could it you know
when if nestmates die or some if there's
like an
alarm and so it's like it if flocking is
the goal
then yeah well I think it I think
there's a link back to the cognitive
capacity um and level of
abstraction in other words if I'm if I
don't understand more than two Dimension
two
dimensions then you I can only
reconfigure two
Dimensions maybe ever thought but anyway
just a
thought
H yeah Hector um he he's been sharing
some resources about the development
that happens in a child between like the
ages of four and seven as they're
separating out like beliefs from
knowledge where they'll do the
experiment like a little character sees
somebody put a ball into a box then the
character leaves the room and then the
the ball is moved and the character
comes back and then you ask like where
does the character think the ball is
and then it it's kind of like theory of
mind like you have to understand that
well the ball is really in a different
place but they think it's
here so then that
um that a l it's the holding up of
multiple possible beliefs about where
that ball
is but if you didn't have the capacity
to
entertain and like to juxtapose the
memory of the ball moving with when they
left the room and all that
then you would collapse down to either
the ball being you know to to to
incorrect answer to that question but
then what's interesting about it is like
one day the child will not be able to do
it and then like two weeks later the
child will be able to do that and then
that capacity will never leave them for
their
life just like on a random day when
they're five years
old
yeah okay cool well fun chapter 3
interesting High Road um hopefully we
got to some good
topics uh chapter
4 is is kind of like where the high and
low road are G to they're going to merge
back
together and chapter 4 is going to
be the
um the formal treatment as they say of
the generative models and that's going
to include some kind of like background
material on the causal
graphs and then come to like figure 4.3
which is like the Rosetta Stone image
with a discrete time and the continuous
time generative
models so these are two possible
architectures that treat time
differently that have the kind of top
down characteristics that were discussed
on the high
road and have that low road mod
construction
so thank you all see you next time
thanks Danel bye
byebye